Scott E. Roberts

Email: s.e.roberts0@gmail.com

GitHub: https://www.github.com/ScotteRoberts | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-e-roberts

OBJECTIVE

Currently seeking an associate developer / associate software engineer position in hopes of creating long-lasting, secure solutions that improve the lives of users. Five years of experience in application programming with three years of specialization in web development. Acquired skills developing secure, extensible, and scalable solutions while following the Agile software design principles using Scrum project management practices.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Dev Languages: JavaScript (ES6+), Typescript, HTML, Liquid, CSS, C#, Bash, Python, Java, SQL

Dev Tools: Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, GitHub, Postman, Google Suite

Dev Technologies: Angular, Polymer, React.js, Vue.js, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, Bulma.io, Elasticsearch

Cloud: Heroku, Netlify, AWS EC2, Buddy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Warner Media | Software Engineer, Front End

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Provided solutions that helped refine and simplify internal image workflow tools for Warner Media teams including: HBO Max, DC Comics, Home Entertainment, and more
- Led stakeholder meeting demonstrations explaining UI features of the internal DAM system which guided requirements gathering and key decision making for development
- Performed the same tasks listed under "Warner Media Talent Path | Front End Web Developer Consultant"

Warner Media - Talent Path | Front End Web Developer Consultant

Jan. 2020 – Jan. 2022

- Collaborated with a development/product team of 6-10 people to maintain and improve the UI/UX of an internal Digital Asset Management (DAM) application used by ~1000 employees
- Developed front-end components and pages using various front-end frameworks such as Angular, Polymer, React, Bootstrap
- Configured application search capabilities with Elastic Search to deliver fast results
- Collaborated in the design and integration between the technology suite of the Digital Media Supply Chain

Happy Howl | Lead Software Engineer / CTO

Sep. 2019 – Present

- Co-lead the curation of the technology ecosystem used by Happy Howl for internal employees and ecommerce customers
- Configured a Shopify store and its various applications to fit the needs of the business owner which resulted in over \$60,000 sales
- Created a proxy Express server to integrate the subscription-based ordering logic of Shopify's, ReCharge's (3rd party subscription vendor) and our personal APIs
- Implemented a Shopify store theme built with Liquid and React components
- Organized the weekly scrum activities, using Jira, to provide a productive workflow for development team members and visibility of work for the business owner

Talent Path | Lead Software Engineer

July 2019 – Jan. 2020

 Created and developed full-stack web development training materials while assisting in group and peer-to-peer instruction

- Facilitated weekly one-on-one code review sessions to document project progression, learning retention, and various benchmarks and measure a steady "work-ready" progression
- Consulted remotely on curriculum development and training with another training team in a
 Talent Path branch to build a scalable curriculum

Talent Path | Full-stack Engineer

Jan. 2019 – June 2019

- Collaborated with an Agile team to successfully develop an app from conception to production
- Built full-stack applications with React, Node, Express, and MongoDB
- Implemented advanced CSS including grid, flexbox, and responsive design
- Performed unit and end-to-end testing with Jest
- Managed projects via GitHub by leveraging Kanban boards, source control, and issue tracking
- Deployed apps using cloud tools such as Heroku and Netlify

EDUCATION

California State University, Long Beach

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Cumulative GPA: 3.8

Graduated: May 2018